Guide to the William Coleman research files CBHM.0032
Center for Brooklyn History
- Series 2: Secondary sources, 1900-2021
  - Sub-series 2.4: Reviews, 1928-2018 (Box 6)
    Carlson, Thomas C., [Review of] Poe and His Times: The Artist and His Milieu by Benjamin Fisher. The Mississippi Quarterly 46.1, Winter 1992.
    Crain, Caleb, There She Blew: The History of American Whaling [review of Leviathan by Eric Jay Dolin]. The New Yorker, July 23, 2007.
    Cray, Robert E. Jr., Reviews of Books: Generous Enemies: Patriots and Loyalists in Revolutionary New York by Judith L. Van Buskirk. The William and Mary Quarterly 60.2, 2003.
    Dain, Bruce, Reviews of Books: Stories of Freedom in Black New York by Shane White and In the Shadow of Slavery: African Americans in New York City, 1626-1863 by Leslie M. Harris. The William and Mary Quarterly 60.4, 2003.
    Dargis, Manohla, The Imperfect Soul Who Helped Bring an End to the Slave Trade [review of movie Amazing Grace about William Wilberforce]. The New York Times, February 23 2007.
    Dorson, Richard M., Seba Smith [review of the book by that title by Milton and Patricia Rickels]. The Journal of American History 65.2, September 1978.
    Erben, Patrick M., Reviews of Books: Becoming German by Philip Otterness. The William and Mary Quarterly 62.1, circa 2005.
    Finnegan, William, Double-Cross in the Congo [review of The Mission Song by John le Carre]. The New York Review of Books 54.6, April 12 2007.
    Fireman, Janet R., Book Reviews: California, In-Doors and Out by Eliza B. Farnham. The Journal of San Diego History 20.1, Winter 1974.
    Fredrickson, George M., America's Original Sin [review of Challenging the Boundaries of Slavery by David Brion Davis, Generations of Captivity by Ira Berlin, and The Slaveholding Republic by Don E. Fehrenbacher. The New York Review of Books, March 25 2004.
    Fredrickson, George M., The Long Trek to Freedom [review of Though the Heavens May Fall by Steven M. Wise, Slave Country by Adam Rothman, The First Emancipator by Andrew Levy, and Bound for Canaan by Fergus M. Bordewich]. The New York Review of Books, July 14 2005.
    Fredrickson, George M., They'll Take Their Stand [review of Inhuman Bondage by David Brion Davis and The Mind of the Master Class by Elizabeth Fox-Genovese and Eugene D. Genovese]. The New York Review of Books, May 25, 2006.
    Fredrickson, George M., Redcoat Liberation [review of Epic Journeys of Freedom by Cassandra Pybus, Rough Crossings by Simon Schama, and The Forgotten Fifth by Gary B. Nash]. The New York Review of Books, August 10 2006.
    Furbank, P.N., A Capacity for Impudence [review of Beaumarchais in Seville by Hugh Thomas]. The New York Review of Books, April 26 2007.
    Gewen, Barry, The Everyman of Genocide [review of Becoming Eichmann by David Cesarani]. The New York Times Book Review, May 14 2006.
    Gillespie, Michelle, Reviews of Books: Slavery, Freedom and Culture among Early American Workers by Graham Russell Hodges. The William and Mary Quarterly 58.1, January 2001.
    Hamill, Pete, Raging Thirst [review of Dry Manhattan by Michael A. Lerner]. The New York Times, March 11 2007.
    Heig, Aline, Review: The Cuba Commission Report: A Hidden History of the Chinese in Cuba by The Cuba Commission and Indentured Labor, Caribbean Sugar by Walton Look Lai. The Hispanic American Historical Review 75.4, November 1995. Herbert, Bob, In America; Stanton and Anthony. The New York Times, July 4 1999.
    Kazin, Michael, The Original Party Boss [review of Martin Van Buren by Ted Widmer]. The New York Times Book Review, February 27 2005.
    Kirsch, A., The Battle Cry of Freedom [review of The Slaves' War by Andrew Ward]. The New York Sun, June 4 2008. Lurie Alison, Liberated Girls [review of Little Women, Little Men, Jo's Boys by Louisa May Alcott]. The New York Review of Books, November 3 2005.
    Marietta, Jack D., [Review of] "Rememb'ring our Time and Work is the Lords": The Experiences of Quakers on the Eighteenth-Century Pennsylvania Frontier by Guenther Karen. Journal of American History 93.3, December 2006.
    May, Robert E., Antebellum Americans 'Meet' Their Southern Neighbors [review of Agents of Manifest Destiny by Charles H. Brown]. Reviews in American History 8.3, September 1980.
    McPherson, James M., The Fight for Slavery in California [review of The California Gold Rush by Leonard L. Richards]. TheNew York Review of Books, October 11 2007.
    McPherson, James M., Days of Wrath [review of John Brown, Abolitionist by David S. Reynolds, John Brown by Merrill D. Peterson, and Terrible Swuft Sword ed. Peggy Russo]. The New York Review, May 12 2005.
    Merwick, Donna, Reviews of Books: Zion on the Hudson by Firth Haring Fabend. The William and Mary Quarterly 58.2, 2001.
    Miller, Joseph C., [Review of] The Slave Trade by Hugh Thomas. The Journal of American History 85.2, September 1998.
    Moorehead, Caroline, Amnesia in Australia [review of multiple books on Australian history]. The New York Review of Books 53.18, November 16 2006.
    Olson, Alison G., Reviews of Books: The Imperial Executive in America by Mary Lou Lustig and General Sir Guy Carleton by David Paul Nelson. The William and Mary Quarterly 60.4, 2003.
    Parks, Tim, The Illusionist [review of 3 biographies of Mussolini]. The New York Review of Books, April 7 2005.
    Reynolds, David S., Family Business [review of Sons of Providence by Charles Rappleye]. The New York Times Book Review, May 14, 2006.
    Reynolds, David S., Fine Specimens [review of The Afterlives of Specimens by Linday Tuggle and Drum-Taps by Walt Whitman, ed. Lawrence Kramer]. The New York Review, March 22 2018.
    Rushforth, Brett, Reviews of Books: The Indian Slave Trade: The Rise of the English Empire in the American South, 1670-1717 by Alan Gallay. The William and Mary Quarterly 60.3, 2003.
    Ryden, David, Running the Numbers: An Overview of The Trans-Atlantic Slave Trade CD-ROM. Slavery and Abolition 22.3, December 2001.
    Schlesinger, A.M., [Review of] Two American Pioneers: Seba Smith and Elizabeth Oakes Smith by Mary Alice Wyman. The New England Quarterly 1.2, April 1928.
    Swift, Daniel, "Stephen Spender": The Poet of Autobiography [review of Stephen Spender by John Sutherland]. The New York Times [2 copies], February 27 2005.
    Wheatcroft, Geoffrey, Digging for Moles [review of Treachery by Chapman Pincher]. The New York Review of Books 56.16, October 22 2009.
    Wood, Gordon S., What Slavery Was Really Like [review of Mastery, Tyranny and Desire by Trevor Burnard and Landon Carter's Uneasy Kingdom by Rhys Isaac]. New York Times Book Review, November 18 2004.
    Wood, Gordon S., Apologies to the Iroquois [review of The Divided Gorund by Alan Taylor]. New York Review of Books, April 6 2006.
    Wood, Gordon S., Reading the Founders' Minds [review of Dark Bargain by Lawrence Goldstone and American Taxation, American Slavery by Robin L. Einhorn]. New York Review of Books, June 28 2007.
  - Sub-series 2.5: Theses and dissertations, 1894-2007 (Box 6)
    Carroll, Aileen M. Gentle Rebel: Elizabeth Oakes Smith. Masters Thesis at the University of Maine Orono, 1968.
    Du Bois, W.E.B. Appendix A: A Chronological Conspectus of Colonial and State Legislation Restricting the African Slave-Trade. 1641-1787. In The Suppression of the African Slave-Trade, PhD dissertation at Harvard, 1894.
    Eltis, David. The Transatlantic Slave Trade, 1821-1863. PhD dissertation at University of Rochester, 1978.
    Hohl, Loz. The Temperate Feminist: Elizabeth Oakes Smith. Master's essay at Sarah Lawrence College, 1977.
    Johnson, Erica Robin. Louisiana Identity on Trial: The Superior Court Case of Pierre Benomine Dormenon 1790-1812. Master's thesis at University of Texas Arlington, 2007.
    Kirkland, Leigh. A Human Life: Being the Autobiography of Elizabeth Oakes Smith. A Critical Edition and Introduction. PhD thesis [order form only].
    Moss, Richard Shannon. Slavery on Long Island: Its Rise and Decline during the Seventeenth Through Nineteenth Centuries [order form and notes].
    Richards, Wynola L. A Review of the Life and Writing of Elizabeth Oakes Smith. PhD dissertation at Ball State University, 1981.
- Series 3: William Coleman notes and correspondence, circa 2000s-2020 (Box 6)
  - William Coleman writings
    2007 memo to Deborah Schwartz re: NYHS exhibit on slavery; text of 2008 speech at BHS.
  - Research correspondence
    Printouts of emails between Coleman and other scholars and associates.
  - Notes on publications
    Notes on the following:
    Bernstein, R.B. Thomas Jefferson. Oxford University Press, 2003.
    Brasseuax, Carl A. The Road to Louisiana: the Saint-Domingue Refugees, 1792-1809. University of Louisiana at Lafayette, 1992.
    Drake, Philip. Captain Richard Drake, Revelations of a Slave Smuggler. Robert M. Dewitt, 1860.
    DuBois, W.E.B. Suppression of the Slave Trade, 1638-1870. Langmans, Green & Co., 1896.
    Jameson, J. Franklin. Narratives of New Netherland, 1609-1664. Charles Scribner's Sons, 1909.
    McGuire, James K. The Democratice Party of the State of New York. U.S. History Co., 1905.
    McManus, Edgar J. History of Negro Slavery in New York. Syracuse University Press, 1996.
    Miller, New York Considered and Improved 1689. The Burrows Brothers Company, 1903.
    Mins, Stewart L. Cobert's West India Policy. Yale University Press, 1912.
    O'Callaghan, E.B. New York Colonial Tracts Number III. J. Muncell, 1867.
    Pitman, Frank Wesley. The Development of the British West Indies 1700-1763. Yale University Press, 1917.
    Scoville, Joseph Alfred. Old Merchants of New York City. Thomas R. Knox, 1885.
    Todd, Charles Burr. The Story of the City of New York. G.P. Putnam's Sons, 1888.
    Townsend, Craig. Faith in Their Own Color. Columbia University Press, 2005.
  - Notes on research topics
    Arranged alphabetically.
    Notes, correspondence and documents regarding the Nathaniel Gordon case, Appleton Oaksmith and Elizabeth Oakes Smith, David Eltis's Trans-Atlantic Slave Trade Database ("comments and backup materials"), and general information on shipping and the slave trade.